# **Prakash Upadhyay**

Full Stack Engineer - 9 Years

+91 8861006191

prakash.upadhyay93@yahoo.com

in linkedin.com/in/upadhyayprakash

Mumbai, India

I'm a full-stack developer with **9 years** of experience in building scalable web and backend applications. Primary tech-stack: **MERN** and **Cloud-native** tech. Built retail analytics dashboards, complex video streaming web app, an aircraft incident optimisation system and e-2-e payment experience. I like hackathons and believe in team innovation.

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

## Gojek

Senior Full Stack Developer | May 2022- Present

- Revamped GoPay payments app handling 5.6 million transaction/day
- Reduced latency from 300ms to 63ms on average.
- Built OnePin 2FA system to reduce SMS OTP costs.
- Tech stack: Java, ReactJS, AWS, Istio, GitLab CI/CD.

## **PayTM Insider**

Senior Full Stack Developer | Apr 2021 - Apr 2022

- Built highly scalable live video platform for virtual events.
- Supported **50+ concurrent** hosts and 3K+ viewers.
- Implemented video layout engine for dynamic video tile rendering.
- Tech stack: ReactJS, 100ms, Akamai CDN.

#### **InkersAl**

Fullstack Developer | Apr 2019 - May 2020

- Created retail analytics dashboard using computer vision Al.
- Tracked real-time customer engagement and dwell times.
- Delivered real-time heat map and periodic reports.
- Tech stack: React, NodeJS, VisionAl models, Docker.

## SAP Labs (ICN ML Team)

Software Developer | Dec 2017 - June 2018

- Worked on ML model management and training pipelines.
- REST APIs for ML model life-cycle management, CLI for the REST APIs(GoLang).
- Deliverables: Image Annotation Tool(RequireJS), Gas Meter Reading Model, Apparel Detection
- Tech stack: RequireJS, Java, Python, S3, EC2

#### CERTIFICATION

- Learning Kubernetes by Kim Schlesinger (LinkedIn)
- Vision Al Externship (InkersAl)

## SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python

ReactJS, NextJS, CSR/SSR

NodeJS/NestJS/Laravel

MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Redis

Docker, Kubernetes, AWS

Git, Jira, Confluence, Postman, Figma

#### **PATENT & AWARDS**

Voice-enabled User Interface Framework (USPTO: 10936288)

09/2016

SAP Global IoT Challenge'16
WINNER in Logistics

SudoCode 3.0 WINNER

06/2016

CodeForCharity 2.0 - WINNER

05/2016

## **EDUCATION**

#### **B.E in Computer Science**

Vivekanand Education Society's Institute of Technology 2010 - 2014

## LANGUAGES

English (Professional)
Hindi (Native)

## INTERESTS

Teaching
Cycling / Snooker